Welcome back. My name is Mahni and I work on the prediction team at Mercedes.
欢迎回来 我叫 Mahni 在 Mercedes 公司的预测团队工作
To understand what the prediction team does,
如果大家想要了解我们团队的工作
imagine at T-shaped intersection.
那么 请设想一个 T 型的路口
You are a self-driving car that has just pulled up to the stop sign.
并设想你是一辆无人驾驶汽车 刚在停车标志前停下
You want to turn left but your sensors notice another vehicle coming from the left.
你想要左转 但是你身上的传感器监测到 从左边道路上来了一辆车
Now, let's pause for a moment.
现在 我们先暂停一下
At this point, you as a human probably know the green vehicle will do one of two things,
这种情况下 作为我们人类 大家可能都清楚 绿车将会做以下两种动作之一
either it will go straight or it will go right.
直行 或者右转
Well, let's say that at this point,
那么 让我们继续设想
the green vehicle starts slowing down and moving right in the lane.
这时候绿车开始减速 并沿道路右侧行驶
Well, you probably know that they are
这时候 大家可能都已经猜到了
turning right which means it is safe for you to go left.
这辆车在右转 意味着你可以很安全地左转了
By making a successful prediction,
通过这种良好的预测
you were able to make a decision that got you to your destination safely and efficiently.
我们就能做出正确决策 并安全高效地到达目的地
And what makes prediction interesting but also
预测工作非常有趣 但也极富挑战性
challenging is that it is inherently multi-modal.
因为 它天生就是多模式的
A good way of thinking about what that
要透彻理解这一点
means is to think of how you would answer the question,
请思考一下你会如何回答下述问题
"Where is the green car likely to be in five seconds?"
5秒之后 绿车的位置可能会在哪里？
If we try to come up with the probability distribution,
如果我们试着绘出目标位置的概率分布图
we would see that it has multiple peaks or moats.
我们将在图上看到多个尖峰或者深沟
If the car is going straight,
如果该车直行
then the car is likely to be somewhere here.
那么它可能会出现在这一片
But if the car turns right,
但是 如果该车右转
then it's more likely to be here.
那么它更有可能出现在这里
And in general, the way we think about handling multi-modal uncertainty is
总之 我们处理这种多模型不确定性的方式
by maintaining some beliefs about how probable each potential mode is.
就是针对每种潜在模式的可能性大小 持续维护一些判断
Initially, if we just see this green car coming from far away,
一开始 如果我们只是看到这辆绿色小车从远处驶来
those beliefs could be initialized using some prior knowledge about this intersection.
我们可能会使用该路口相关的已知信息 对这些判断进行初始化操作
In this case, let's say that cars generally go straight at this intersection.
就上述例子而言 假设我们已知该路口的汽车通常会直行
But as we continue watching the car,
但是 当我们持续跟踪该车
we may notice that it is slowing down.
我们也许会监测到 它开始减速
Since this behavior is more consistent with turning right,
因为减速这种行为更符合右转的情况
the probability of turning right increases.
所以 我们会增加右转几率
And then, at the next timestep,
接着 在下一个监测时间点上
we might notice that the car has already started turning
我们或许监测到 该车已经开始右转了
right which again increases the probability of turning right.
这进一步增加了右转几率
And as we keep observing,
就这样 我们不断监测
we continue updating our belief based on new evidence until eventually we
并根据新信息持续更新我们的判断
can predict with high certainty that the vehicle is turning right at this intersection.
直到最后 我们几乎可以确定 该车会在这个路口右转
So the responsibility of the prediction module is to do the
从上面例子 大家可以看出 预测模块的工作过程如下
following: We take as input a map of the world and data from sensor fusion
首先 预测模块会输入地图数据 以及传感器融合数据
and generate as output some predictions of the future state of
然后 预测模块会生成并输出一些预测数据
all the vehicles and other moving objects in the vicinity of our vehicle.
这些预测数据包含了周围所有其他机动车以及其他移动物体的未来状态
Typically, these predictions are represented by a set
通常 这些预测数据可展示为若干可能的运动轨迹
of possible trajectories like that two dotted arrows
正如大家所见 从绿色汽车引出的
emanating from the green car in this scenario and
这两条带箭头的虚线
an associated probability for each trajectory.
预测数据还包括每条轨迹伴随的几率大小
Before we get into the details,
在我们进一步详细说明之前
let me explain what we are going to discuss in this lesson.
我先大概讲一下本课程中我们将要学习的内容
First, we'll go through a brief overview where you will learn
首先是简介 通过简介 大家可以了解到
a bit more about the inputs and outputs to prediction.
预测过程的输入和输出
Next, we will talk about how prediction is actually done.
接着 我会讲到实际的预测过程
We will discuss the two main classes of prediction techniques,
我们会讨论两类主要的预测技术
model-based approaches and data-driven approaches.
基于模型法 以及数据驱动法
There, model-based approaches use mathematical models of motion to predict
基于模型法使用运动数学模型
trajectories and data-driven approaches rely
来预测运动轨迹
on machine learning and examples to learn from.
而数据驱动法则依赖于机器学习和案例学习
Then, I will briefly walk you through how to apply
接着 我会简要介绍一下如何应用严格的数据驱动法
strictly data-driven approach for prediction called trajectory clustering.
来进行预测工作
Then, we will dig into model-based approaches where I'll introduce
然后 我会深入讲解基于模型法
process models as a mathematical technique for modeling
我会引入一门称为“过程模型”的数学技术 来模型化不同的动作
various maneuvers like lane changes, vehicle following, etc.
比如 车道变换 跟随驾驶等
And introduce multi-modal estimators as
我还会引入一种实用技术——多模估量器
an effective technique for handling the uncertainty associated with prediction,
来处理预测伴随的不确定性
namely, the uncertainty about which maneuver an object will do in a particular situation.
也就是说 在特定情况下 目标将做何种动作的几率
Finally, we will dive deep into hybrid approaches
最后 我会详细讲解多方法混合
which use data and process models to predict motion
混合法使用数据和过程模型来预测运动
through a cycle of intense classification where we try to
预测过程通过一个密集计算的分类循环完成
figure out what a driver wants to do and trajectory generation.
该循环的主要工作是预测司机的动向并生成轨迹
There we try to figure out how they are likely to do it.
在该部分 我会指出这些方法可能的工作方式
We will end by implementing an algorithm called Naive Bayes to
结束时候 我们会实现一个称为 Naive Bayes 的算法
predict the motion of a car at a T-shaped intersection like the one you just saw.
并用它去预测一辆行驶在 T 形路口的汽车将如何运动 正如大家刚才所见
In the next few segments,
在接下来的几小节里
I'm going to ask you to do some reading about
我会请大家读一些
the data processing that happens in a typical prediction module.
典型预测模块内与数据处理相关的材料